Brandon Caples

SHOPIFY DEVELOPER

(423) 281-5150 brandon.caples@gmail.com brandoncaples.com







I'm a self-motivated frontend web developer and web content administrator with 6 years of experience working in teams and individually to manage Shopify and WordPress websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Liquid, and web apps.

SKILLS

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPMENT | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Liquid, MVC, WordPress, Shopify, Timber/Twig, Ruby & Ruby on Rails, Liquid, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Firebase, SVG animation

EMAIL DEVELOPMENT | HTML, CSS, troubleshooting, VML, AMPscript, Adobe Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Git, SQL, responsive design, detail oriented

PROJECT MANAGEMENT | Project planning, collaboration, Kanban, Agile, problem solving, delegation, training, documentation, Asana, TaskRay

ANALYTICS & DATA | Excel, Google Analytics, reporting, SQL/SOQL, Google Tag Manager, JavaScript, data analysis

GRAPHIC DESIGN | Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, GIMP, website design, digital and print ad design, printed newsletter design, document layout design

CERTIFICATIONS

Marketing Cloud Email Specialist Salesforce, 2024

Email Marketer HubSpot Academy, 2023

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts: Organizational Communication for Consulting & Research, Minor: Marketing Lipscomb University — 2011

EXPERIENCE

Senior Email & SMS Developer

Promoted from Digital Media & Web Developer in June 2024

Precept Ministries International — Chattanooga, Tennessee (Remote) December 2019 - PRESENT

Frontend Web Development

- Design and develop page layouts and components for Shopify, WordPress, and other platforms
- Maintain frontend code integrity, including testing and troubleshooting
- Develop new web components for fundraising campaigns, including countdown timers and SVG animations
- Update website content and ensure quality standards are met, including performance and accessibility
- Build and update web forms and manage data submissions

Email Development

- Modernized email development processes, improving render consistency across ESPs
- Created and maintain a component library for building HTML email templates
- Built 750+ responsive and performant emails
- Launched and warmed a new email IP

Analytics & Data

- Streamlined the UTM tagging process and developed new tracking standards
- Write SQL queries to pull complex data reports and automate marketing flows
- Transitioned six web properties to Google Analytics 4 and write custom tracking scripts

Team Leadership

- Train and mentor the Digital Content Platform Specialist in technical frontend skills and content management
- Provide guidance to team members for project delivery and prioritization

Brandon Caples

SHOPIFY DEVELOPER

(423) 281-5150 brandon.caples@gmail.com brandoncaples.com





Web Designer/Developer

Caples Web Design — Remote

April 2018 - PRESENT

I designed, developed, and enhanced WordPress websites for clients, migrated sites to WordPress, redesigned page layouts, and employed SEO best practices to improve search engine rankings.

Web Content Specialist

Mercy Multiplied America — Nashville, Tennessee

April 2018 - December 2019

I maintained WordPress website code and content, designed page layouts, optimized for search engines, and managed digital ads.

- Managed Shopify products, collections, and pages, adding custom code and testing third-party apps as needed
- Designed page layouts for Shopify and WordPress sites, redesigned the WordPress theme
- Designed and developed new WordPress content directories for mercymultiplied.com
- Created and maintained event registration pages and donation forms with Luminate Online
- Trained and mentored the project manager to transition into email development

Digital Marketing Specialist

Columbia Coatings, LLC — Columbia, Tennessee

June 2017 - February 2018

I managed all email marketing, created website content, designed marketing graphics, and trained new associates for phone sales.

- Retouched product photos and managed 4,000+ ecommerce products and general website performance
- Managed concept, design, and implementation of weekly email newsletter

Director of Client Communications, Deering Wealth Team

Southwestern Investment Group — Franklin, Tennessee

January 2016 - June 2017

I designed and launched a new WordPress website, wrote for the financial blog, coordinated client events, managed social media, and designed business collateral.

- Migrated content from Squarespace to WordPress
- Wrote and designed email communications, event collateral, website content, and blog posts

Marketing Director

Batson Chiropractic Group — Nashville, Tennessee

August 2013 - January 2016

Wrote for blogs and the print newsletter, managed social media, and designed marketing collateral, among other duties.

- Launched nashvillebraincore.com and created its content
- Automated the new patient intake process, avoiding human error and time costs during intake
- Designed marketing collateral, including website content, direct mail, newsletters, signage, email graphics, ads, etc.